rapport3.com 2016-04-10

# Project management for construction, architects and engineers. Privacy Policy Rapport3 by Cubic Interactive.

## **Privacy Policy**

**What we collect**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Websites.
  * If you contact us through our Websites, whether by sending messages to our email addresses, filling in any forms, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of your visits to our Websites including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data and the resources that you access.

**Third party websites**

Our Website contains links that make it easy for you to visit the websites of our partner networks, affiliates and clients. If you use the links to visit any website operated by a third party, please check the privacy policy of that third party and satisfy yourself that the terms are acceptable to you before you use or submit any personal data to such website. We do not have any control over such third party websites. Information you provide or which may be collected by such website is controlled by the relevant third party provider of such website. Accordingly, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide or which may be collected by the third party provider while visiting or using such websites.

You may inform us at any time should you wish us to delete personal information we hold about you by writing to **Cubic Interactive Ltd, The Sanctuary, 23 OakHill Grove, Surbiton, Surrey, KT6 6DU.**

You have a right to access the personal data held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please write to Cubic Interactive Ltd, The Sanctuary, 23 Oak Hill Grove, Surbiton, Surrey, KT6 6DU. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**IP addresses and cookies**

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual.

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Under new UK legislation, the cookies we use on this website all fall into ‘category 1 – strictly necessary’ and ‘category 2 – performance cookies’.  Category 2 cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages.  These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works.  By using our website you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | More information  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
Content Management System cookie | Wp-settings-1wp-settings-time-1 

vc_widget_generic-expert

| This cookie is set by our content management system on some browsers, upon arrival to our site. It is not used by Cubic Interactive for any purpose.  
  
**YouTube cookies**

We embed videos from our YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit [YouTube’s embedding videos information page](http://www.google.com/support/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780).

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies.

**Where we store your personal data**

The data that we collect from you is stored on our secure servers which are located in the UK, all staff who process your data are employed in the UK and therefore comply with UK data protection legislation.  By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Websites; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Uses made of the information**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We do not pass information onto third party groups or advertisers.

If you are an existing customer, we will contact you by electronic means (e-mail) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you or with information concerning your purchase including software upgrades.

**Your rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by writing to Cubic Interactive Ltd, The Sanctuary, 23 Oak Hill Grove, Surbiton, Surrey, KT6 6DU.

**Disclosure of your information**

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

In the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party purchaser, the personal data of our customers will be one of the transferred assets.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect our rights, property, or safety (or that of our customers and others). This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

Cubic Interactive may change their privacy policy from time to time by updating this page.  This policy is effective from 1st May 2012.  Last update to this page  1st July 2014.
